Guide to the British Correspondence and Miscellany Collection, 1556-1972 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Correspondence Series, 1556-1972 and undated
  - Melbourne, William, 1820-1853 and undated, (10 items) (Box 2)
  - Midleton, Lord Broderick, 1887-1912 and undated, (12 letters, an undated stereograph of Broderick attached to letter of August 17, 1897 to Major Thomson) (Box 2)
  - Milner, Alfred Milner, Viscount, 1903-1908 and undated, (5 items) (Box 2)
  - Murray, David Christie, 1881-1907 and undated, (8 letters, a group of handwritten biographical notes, a clipping from unidentified newspaper of 9 August, 1910 announcing a lecture series, a 1908 printed review of Murray's Reflections.) (Box 2)
  - Napier of Magdala - Nicholson, 1706-1885 and undated
    - Napier of Magdala (Box 2)
    - Neale, Harry Burrard, 2nd Baronet (Box 2)
    - Neel, Lt. General (Box 2)
    - Newcastle Under Lyme, Henry Fiennes Pelham-Clinton, 2nd Duke (recipient) (Box 2)
    - Newcastle Under Lyme, Thomas Holles, 1st Duke (Box 2)
    - Nicholson (Box 2)
  - Northbrook - Nose, 1781-1900 and undated
    - Northbrook, Thomas George Baring, Earl (Box 2)
    - Northbrook, Francis Thornhill (Box 2)
    - Northumberland, Hugh Percy, 2nd Duke (Box 2)
    - Northumberland, Henry George Percy, 7th Duke (Box 2)
    - Norwich (Box 2)
    - Nose, George (Box 2)
  - Nimmo, Thomas, 1845-1856, (5 items) (Box 2)
  - Northcote, Stafford Henry and Henry Stafford, Barons Northcote, 1843-1855 and undated, (7 items) (Box 2)
  - O'Connor - Olozaga, 1852-1881 and undated
    - O'Connor, Thomas Power (Box 2)
    - O'Dowd, James (Box 2)
    - Oglethorpe, Charles (recipient) (Box 2)
    - O'Hagan, Thomas, 1st Baron (recipient) (Box 2)
    - Oliviera (Box 2)
    - Olozaga, Don Salustiano (Box 2)
  - Onslow - Oswald, 1748-1863 and undated
    - Onslow, Arthur (Box 2)
    - Osborne, Sydney Godolphin (Box 2)
    - Oswald, John (Box 2)
  - O'Mahoney, Pierce, 1911-1938, (5 items) (Box 2)
  - Paley - Palmer, 1775-1902 and undated
    - Paley, H.W. (Box 2)
    - Palgram, Francis (Box 2)
    - Pallifer, Hugh (Box 2)
    - Palmer, Greville (Box 2)
  - Partridge - Patterson, 1788-1939 and undated
    - Partridge, Benard (Box 2)
    - Patten, Dr. Thomas (Box 2)
    - Patterson, J. (Box 2)
  - Pelham-Clinton - Philipson, 1752-1888 and undated
    - Pelham-Clinton, Edward, Lord (Box 2)
    - Pelham (Box 2)
    - Penn (Box 2)
    - Pennington (Box 2)
    - Pepe, Guglielmo (Box 2)
    - Phillipps (Box 2)
    - Phillips, Alexander (Box 2)
    - Philpot, William (Box 2)
    - Philipson, John Burton (Box 2)
  - Player - Portland, 1812-1876 and undated
    - Player, T. (Box 2)
    - Playfair, Lyon, 1st Baron Playfair (Box 2)
    - Plowden, Chichele (Box 2)
    - Pole, Reginald Chanclos (Box 2)
    - Pollock, Fred (Box 2)
    - Portland, William Henry Cavendish Scott (Box 2)
  - Palmerston, Henry John Temple, 3rd Viscount, 1823-1877 and undated, (14 items) (Box 2)
  - Platt-Higins, 1892-1922, (7 items) (Box 2)
  - Pollock, Jonathon Frederick, 1st Baronet, 1806-1851 and undated, (15 items) (Box 2)
  - Porter, George Richardson, 1828-1860 and undated, (15 items) (Box 2)
  - Radnor - Rivers, 1740-1890 and undated
    - Radnor, William Folkstone (Box 2)
    - Reade (recipient) (Box 2)
    - Count Reckburg, Austrian Minister for Foreign Affairs (Box 2)
    - Red Jacket (pseudonym) (Box 2)
    - Reels, R. (Box 2)
    - Reid, Wermyn (recipient) (Box 2)
    - Richmond, Charles Henry Gordon-Lennox, 6th Duke (Box 2)
    - Richmond, Charles Lennox, 2nd Duke (Box 2)
    - Ridley, Matthew White, 2nd Viscount (Box 2)
    - Riley, Henry Thomas (Box 2)
    - Ripon, Frederick John Robinson, 1st Earl (Box 2)
    - Ripon, George Frederick Samuel Robinson, 2nd Earl (Box 2)
    - Rivers, Earl (Box 2)
  - Robertson - Rupell, Earl of, 1782-1907 and undated
    - Robertson, John (Box 2)
    - Robinson, Jack (Box 2)
    - Rockingham, Marchioness of (1784) (Box 2)
    - Rodd, James (Box 2)
    - Rodriguez, Angel Maria de (Box 2)
    - Roebuck, John Arthur (recipient) (Box 2)
    - Rogers, James Edwin Thorold (Box 2)
    - Rolles, Rear Admiral Robert (Box 2)
    - Romer, Robert (Box 2)
    - Romilly, John, 1st Baron (Box 2)
    - Rosebery, Archibald Philip Primrose, 5th Earl (Box 2)
    - Rosslyn, James St. Clair Erskine, 2nd Earl (Box 2)
    - Rothschild, Nathan Meyer, 1st Baron (Box 2)
    - Rover, Trevor (Box 2)
    - Rupell, Earl of (Box 2)
  - Roberts, Frederick Sleigh Roberts, 1st Earl, 1867-1914 and undated, (8 items) (Box 2)
  - Rose, George, 1787-1797 and undated, (12 items) (Box 2)
  - St. John-Shah, 1777-1898 and undated
    - St. John, Spencer (Box 2)
    - Salisbury, Robert Arthur Talbot Gascoyne-Cecil, 3rd Marquess (Box 2)
    - Salt, Henry (Box 2)
    - Sanderson, Thomas Henry, Baron Sanderson (Box 2)
    - Sandhurst, William Rose Mansfield, 1st Baron (Box 2)
    - Sandwich, John Montagu, 4th Earl (Box 2)
    - Saton, E. (Box 2)
    - Schnadhorst (recipient) (Box 2)
    - Schoefield, Joseph (Box 2)
    - Seaford, Charles Rose Ellis, 1st Baron (Box 2)
    - Seburne, Shaw (Box 2)
    - Seeley, John Robert (Box 2)
    - Serle, Ambrose (Box 2)
    - Serle, T. (Box 2)
    - Seymore, Lord Robert (Box 2)
    - Shah, Teroze (Box 2)
  - Shearst - Sophie, 1806-1924 and undated
    - Shearst, Dudley (Box 2)
    - Shee, George (Box 2)
    - Sheil, R.S. (Box 2)
    - Shirley, Henry (Box 2)
    - Sibbald, William (Box 2)
    - Siddons, J.H. (Box 2)
    - Simon, Jules (Box 2)
    - Skelmersdale, Edward Bootle-Wilbraham, 1st Baron (Box 2)
    - Skene, William Forbes (Box 2)
    - Slatin, R. (Box 2)
    - Smith, Sidney (Box 2)
    - Smith, William H. (Box 2)
    - Smyth, Colonel John Rowland (Box 2)
    - Snowden, Philip, 1st Viscount (Box 2)
    - Somerset, Lord Fitzroy James Henry (Box 2)
    - Sophie, Queen (Box 2)
  - Stanhope - Stanley, 1716-1880 and undated
    - Stanhope, James, 1st Earl (Box 2)
    - Stanley, Edward Lyulph, 4th Baron (Box 2)
  - Starke - Sturge, 1771-1923 and undated
    - Starke, Richard (Box 2)
    - Startford de Radcliffe (Box 2)
    - Staurt de Rochesay (Box 2)
    - Stead, John (Box 2)
    - Stead, W.T. (William Thomas) (Box 2)
    - Stephens, Philip (Box 2)
    - Stephenson, Rowland (Box 2)
    - Sticks-Beach, Michael (Box 2)
    - Stockmar, Victoria (Box 2)
    - Stow, Ronald (Box 2)
    - Sturge, Thomas (Box 2)
  - Suniburne - Sutton, 1866-1887 and undated
    - Suniburne, John (Box 2)
    - Sutton, Manners (Box 2)
  - Salisbury, Enoch Robert Gibbon, 1823-1905 and undated, (38 items) (Box 2)
  - Shaftsbury, Ashley, 7th Earl, 1824-1881, (11 items) (Box 2)
  - Sheowring, William, Esq., 1870-1902 and undated, (45 items, including several letters regarding an ongoing lecture series put in Sheowring's charge) (Box 2)
  - Sparkes, J., 1864-1865, (44 items) (Box 2)
  - Spencer, 2nd and 5th Earl, 1795-1895, (14 items) (Box 2)
  - Tapson - Tyrwhitt, 1720-1900 and undated
    - Tapson (Box 2)
    - Thomson (Box 2)
    - Thomson (recipient) (Box 2)
    - Thurlow, Edward, 1st Baron Thurlow (Box 2)
    - Tierney, George (Box 2)
    - Tomkins (recipient) (Box 2)
    - Tomkins, George (recipient) (Box 2)
    - Tomkins (recipient) (Box 2)
    - Torrens, W.M. (William Torrens McCullagh) (Box 2)
    - Torrington, George Byng, Viscount (Box 2)
    - Townshend (recipient) (Box 2)
    - Townshend, Viscount Charles (Box 2)
    - Townshend, Viscount Charles (recipient) (Box 2)
    - Treve (Box 2)
    - Trevelyan, George Otto, 2nd Baronet Trevelyan (Box 2)
    - Trevelyan, Charles Edward, 1st Baronet Trevelyan (Box 2)
    - Turanion, Nicholas (Box 2)
    - Turnbull, M.H. (Box 2)
    - Tyler, James Endell (Box 2)
    - Tyrwhitt, Thomas (Box 2)
  - Teyham, George Henry, 16th Baron Teynham, 1860, (1 item) (Box 2)
  - Thomson, John Deas, 1782-1854 and undated, (19 items, including minutes of a meeting of the Officers of the Royal Marine Mess at Portsmouth) (Box 2)
  - Valentia - Viana, 1782-1920 and undated
    - Valentia, Arthur, 8th Viscount Valentia (Box 2)
    - Valpy, Richard (Box 2)
    - Varna, R. (Box 2)
    - Vautmuri, Desai of (Box 2)
    - Viana, Antonio Jorge (Box 2)
  - Waddington - Wellenbery, 1794-1927 and undated
    - Waddington, M. (Box 2)
    - Wakefield, Rev. Gilbert (Box 2)
    - Walker, Baldwin Wake (Box 2)
    - Walmsley, Joshua (Box 2)
    - Walpole, Spencer Horatio (Box 2)
    - Walsh, Colonel A. (Box 2)
    - Warburton, Henry (Box 2)
    - Warren (Box 2)
    - Watson, W. (Box 2)
    - Webster, Richard (Box 2)
    - Wellenbery (Box 2)
  - Wescott - Wightman, 1793-1902 and undated
    - Westcott, George Blagdon (Box 2)
    - Whiteley, Frank (Box 2)
    - Whitbread, Samuel (Box 2)
    - Whittingham, Samuel Ford (Box 2)
    - Whitworth, Charles, Earl Whitworth (Box 2)
    - Wightman, William (Box 2)
  - Wilbrahenn - Winton, 1760-1910 and undated
    - Wilbrahenn, Roger (Box 2)
    - Williams, Phillip (Box 2)
    - Wilmot, Robert (Box 2)
    - Wilson, C. Rogers (Box 2)
    - Wilson, George (Box 2)
    - Wilson, Guy Fleetwood (recipient) (Box 2)
    - Wilson, Henry J. (Box 2)
    - Wilson, Richard Fountayne (Box 2)
    - Windham, William (recipient) (Box 2)
    - Windham, William (Box 2)
    - Wingate, Francis Reginald (Box 2)
    - Winton (Box 2)
  - Wolff - Wyndham, 1770-1887 and undated
    - Wolff, Drummond (Box 2)
    - Wood, Evelyn (Box 2)
    - Woodford, R. (Box 2)
    - Wordsworth (Box 2)
    - Worms, Henry (Box 2)
    - Wren, C. (Box 2)
    - Wroughton, Thomas (Box 2)
    - Wyndham, George (Box 2)
  - Wellesley, Richard, Marquess Wellesley, 1798-1844 and undated, (11 items, including Wellesley's transcript of a testimonial to the character of Charles Wyatt by the Governor General of India, and a printed poem signed by Wellesley, On the Princess Augusta's Burial in the Royal Tomb, Windsor Castle) (Box 2)
  - Wellington, Arthur Wellesley, 1st Duke, 1808-1849, (2 items) (Box 2)
  - Westbury, 1862-1871 and undated (8 items) (Box 2)
  - Wilberforce, William, 1792-1841 and undated, (11 items, including a letter by the Reverend Samuel Hampton, pasted to the back of Wilberforce's note dated 1807, December 20) (Box 2)
  - Wodehouse, Edward, 1819-1857 and undated, (7 items) (Box 2)
  - Yerburgh - Younge, 1794-1900 and undated
    - Yerburgh (Box 2)
    - York, Frederick, Duke of (Box 2)
    - Young, Russell (Box 2)
    - Younge, Charles Duke (Box 2)
    - Younge, Charlotte Mary (Box 2)
  - Unidentified Correspondence, 1730-1920 and undated, (5 folders) (Box 3)
- Subject Files Series, 1699-1902 and undated
  Papers in this series concern a wide range of political, military, and economic matters and are arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - An Account of Pistols & spyglasses purchased by...officers in Egypt for the purpose of forwarding His Majesty's Service, 1801 (Box 3)
  - Battle of Dettingen, 1743 (Box 3)
  - Bills of Exchange, 1810 (Box 3)
  - County of Somerset, Norton Parish Records, 1699-1729 (Box 3)
  - Crimean War Letters, 1856-1860 and undated (Box 3)
  - Decimal Currency Papers, 1856-1869 (Box 3)
  - Election Certificate, Plumper Vote, 1826 (Box 3)
  - Hemp, undated (Box 3)
  - Line of Battle: Orders, Darby to Goodall, 1781 (Box 3)
  - Marine Requisitions (English and Russian), 1813-1814 (Box 3)
  - Newfoundland Fisheries Question, 1901-1902 (Box 3)
  - Press Gangs, 1745 (Box 3)
  - Royal Navy - Night Signals, 1780 (Box 3)
  - Secretary of State Autographs, 1798-1856 and undated (Box 3)
  - Ship Records, 1815 (Box 3)
  - Treaty between British and Sultan Mehmed, 1810 (Box 3)
  - William White: Obituary, 1890/91 (Box 3)
- Picture Series, 1795-1921 and undated
  This series includes card photographs, engravings, and extractions from volumes. Some pictures have accompanying biographical information. All subjects are British notables. The pictures are arranged alphabetically by the name of the subject.
  - Bovill, Lord Chief Justice (Box 3)
  - Bright, John (Box 3)
  - Cameron, Edward John, 1921 (Box 3)
  - Curzon, Viceroy of India, Lord (Box 3)
  - Dundas, Henry (Box 3)
  - Edwards, Hubers (Box 3)
  - Egypt, Viceroy of (Box 3)
  - Hamley (Box 3)
  - Mansfield, William Murray, 1st Earl (Box 3)
  - Melbourne, William Lamb, Baron (Box 3)
  - Molesworth, William, Bart. (Box 3)
  - Onslow, Arthur (Box 3)
  - Palmerston, Lord (Box 3)
  - Thurlow, Edward, Lord (Box 3)
  - Unidentified (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous Material Series, 1814-1836 and undated
  The material in this series is arranged chronologically.
  - Bank documents 1814, Nov.3-1815, Oct. 29, transferring funds in the name of Philip Rundell, Esq., of London, (7 items) (Box 3)
  - Clippings (1836, Jul. 11 and 23 from the London Times of letters addressed to Lord Hill by Round Robin. The clippings are mounted on a leaf of folded to paper, on which is written what appears to be a draft of a Memorandum regarding the relief of regiments in foreign stations (1836, July 12). (Box 3)
  - Editorial cartoons (undated) depicting Lord Salisbury (Box 3)
  - Biography of Charles Howard, Earl of Nottingham (undated) (Box 3)
- Oversize Material
  - Correspondence Series (Opaperfolder 1)
    - Dey of Algiers, 1806 (Opaperfolder 1)
    - Inglis, John Eardley Wilmot, undated (with accompanying article about Inglis) (Opaperfolder 1)
    - Lenty, John, Captain (Material relating to the ship Sea Witch), 1857 (Opaperfolder 1)
    - Richmond, Charles Lennox, 2nd Duke (to and from), 1740 (Opaperfolder 1)
  - Subject Files Series
    - An Account of Pistols & spyglasses purchased by...officers in Egypt for the purpose of forwarding His Majesty's Service, 1801 (Opaperfolder 1)
    - Line of Battle (Orders, Darby to Goodall, 1781) (Opaperfolder 1)
  - Picture Series
    - Cameron, Edward John, 1921 (Passport) (Opaperfolder 1)